Kevin McGrath

I am a Full-Stack Software developer with a background in Fine Arts; Design; Mathematics; Art and Technology.

<u>Github</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u>

Cell: 708-341-8763 Email: kpmcgra@gmail.com

Location: Chicago, Il.

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, Java, and Javascript | Frameworks/Libraries: Flask, Django, Spring,
Maven, and Bootstrap | Databases: MySql, SQL | Tools: Git, VS Code, Spring Tools, Amazon
Web Services | HTML, CSS, SASS.

Two full-stack development certifications from Coding Dojo in Java and Python using Spring, Maven, and Flask frameworks. Trained in MYSQL and relational databases. Spring Tool Suite for Java development.

I have also studied pure mathematics and formal logic independently for over 10 years and have been a part of two independent recent groups led by mathematics Phd's Lou Kauffman and Eugenia Cheng. I was recently a part of a group that helped Eugenia Cheng get feedback on her recently published book on category theory: "The Joy of Abstraction."

<u>Technical Projects</u>

- <u>Zineverse:</u> a site prototype for independent publishers to host and share their works. Utilizes file management code and file uploads for users to upload images and pages, create pages, update, and delete as they see fit.
 - Python
 - Flask
 - MySQL
 - o HTML/CSS
- <u>FashApp:</u> a group project at Coding Dojo for users to curate clothing into collections and outfits.
 - Python
 - o Flask
 - MySQL
 - o HTML/CSS
 - o Collaborative project utilizing GitHub for version control and collaboration.

Professional Experience

Head Preparator | Carrie Secrist Gallery

2022-Current

- Managed all transportation, construction, packing, staffing and storage for art exhibitions, art installations, and all art related services at Carrie Secrist Gallery.
- Allocated an annual budget of 25,000.00.

Project Manager | Midwest Tropical Custom Water Features 2021-2022

- On-site manager for rigging installations. Designed custom water features with CAD software.
- Project management: Handled purchasing of materials and equipment, promotional graphic design with photoshop and illustrator.

Project Manager and Woodshop Manager | Cadogan Tate Fine Art 2021-2022

- Built and managed the woodshop for crates and general construction. Trained personnel in art handling, safety, and building methods.
- Managed projects, conducted site visits and consultations. Handled all inventory and purchasing for the woodshop: Monthly budget of 10,000.00.

Education

Coding Dojo Full-Stack Developer Certificate	2022-2023
 Web and Software Development in Java and Python 	
School of The Art Institute of Chicago Master of Fine Arts	2017-2019
Illinois State University Bachelors of Science in Fine Arts	2006-2010